<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<submission_xml xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
    xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="submission_schema.xsd">
    <!-- 
    This file is an example of a valid individual submission file. 
    Note the schema file (XSD) pointed to on line 2/3 - TREAT THE SCHEMA AS READ ONLY
    Use this example file as a template and fill with your own data 
    validating as you go along using Oxygen or some other schema aware editor;
	an on-line tool is here: https://www.liquid-technologies.com/online-xsd-validator
    
    DO NOT CHANGE ANY TAGS OR THEIR ORDER BUT ONLY THE CONTENT, OTHERWISE VALIDATION WILL FAIL
    Keep the schema in the same directory as the document as that's where oXygen expects it.
    -->    
    <group id="L"/>
    <student id="24023644"/>
    <!--- Describe one or more group tasks that you contributed to -->
    <group_contribution>
		I helped out with the index.php layout. Spent time messing around with the CSS to get the two maps sitting side by side properly and 
        took a few tries to stop them from stacking weirdly. Made sure the weather sections lined up and didn't look wonky. Kept the navigation 
        bar consistent with what i did on london.php and nyc.php so the whole site feels the same. The dark theme we went with looks decent,
        had to tweak the spacing a bit because things felt too cramped, but in the end we go there and finished it off.
     </group_contribution>
    <!--- Describe your individual component -->
    <individual_component type="Build and integrate a photo widget">
        <description> So i Built a photo widget using the Unsplash API. I looked at both Flickr and Unsplash and chose Unsplash 
            for better photo quality and simpler implementation. The Widget displays 9 photos in a responsive grid 
            for London and New York. Features include loading skeletons, credits with photographer links, 
            and localStorage caching to manage API rate limits. Integrated into london.php and 
            nyc.php, plus created hamza-test.php for independent demonstration. 
        </description>
        <problems> The Main challenges i had were Unsplash rate limits 50 request per hour for a new application,
        inconsistent photo sizes breaking the grid layout, cache path errors in the proxy file that took ages to debug,
         and group database config issues that made integration testing on london.php difficult.
        </problems>
        <solutions>To work around the 50 requests per hour demo mode limit, I implemented localStorage caching with 
            24 hour expiry and now the API only gets called once per day per city. This keeps me well within 
            the rate limits while the app is still in demo mode. Fixed the photo size issue with CSS 
            object fit(cover which makes all images fit neatly in the grid). The cache path errors were 
            resolved by using __DIR__ in the proxy file instead of relative paths. For the group database 
            issues, I created hamza-test.php to demonstrate the widget independently(the group database issues has been resolved)
        </solutions>
        <hours_effort>10</hours_effort>
        <technologies>
            <tech>php</tech>
            <tech>javascript</tech>
            <tech>xml</tech>
            <tech>CSS</tech>
            <tech>Unsplash API</tech>

        </technologies>
        <source_files>
            <file>
                <name>unsplash.php</name>
                <purpose>to fetch unsplash photos</purpose>
            </file>
            <file>
                <name>London.php</name>
                <purpose>Displays London's map, weather forecast, places of interest,
                 and includes my integrated Unsplash photo widget showing London
                 photos at the bottom of the page </purpose>
            </file>
        </source_files>
    </individual_component>
    <security_discussion> When thinking about security for our project, we focused on keeping things simple but protected. 
    We made sure our API keys stay server side in proxy files so they never show up in the browser 
    where someone could grab them. The JavaScript only calls our proxies, not the APIs directly.
    Our GitHub repository is private too so only me and my two teammates can access the code. No random people can see or steal our work, 
    which means we keep control over who has possession of it.
    For the data itself, we wanted to make sure it stays correct and unmodified. 
    The database only gets updated through proper channels, and my photo widget caches photos with timestamps.
    if the cache is older than 24 hours, it fetches fresh ones so users aren't looking at outdated images.
    We also thought about making sure everything is available when needed. The site runs on localhost during development so we always have access.
    For the photo widget, the caching means photos still show up even if Unsplash hits its rate limits or goes down temporarily.
    Users see the last successfully fetched photos instead of broken images.
    We didn't add a login system because there was no real need and nobody needs an account just to look at city information and photos. 
    Would've been extra work for no real benefit.
    </security_discussion>
    <individual_comment> I built a photo widget using the Unsplash API for London and New York. I Looked at Flickr first but switched to Unsplash 
    because the API was way easier to understand and the photos just look better. The caching bit took me ages to figure out because it Kept getting
    file path errors until I found the __DIR__ fix on Stack Overflow.I then added loading skeletons so it doesn't just sit there blank while waiting for photos. 
    I got it working on both london.php and nyc.php, plus made a separate test page to prove it works on its own. 
    The localStorage cache means it only calls Unsplash once per day which keeps me under their rate limits.
    </individual_comment>
</submission_xml>
<!-- DSA Individual XML File Example, 2025-6 -->
<!-- author: prakash.chatterjee@uwe.ac.uk -->
